hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and for those of you who
I haven't met yet this podcast is all
about how to grow in your business
whether you are a coach Mentor trainer
you got content online that you're
trying to monetize we help you build
recurring Revenue so that you don't have
to operate in fight ORF flight you don't
have to struggle but you can actually
live a life that you love that makes you
just feel alive every single day now
today I got a very special treat for you
I got two people that I'm going to pull
up here one is a lady that I've worked
with for a little while her name is
Michelle uh plinsky I I I mess her name
up all the time I think I messed it up
even right there uh I'm gonna I'm gonna
bring her up as well as James curan and
I'm gonna talk about what they do and
we're g to talk together so Michelle and
James how are y'all doing today
welcome up again Michelle you said it
just fine pleas okay cool awesome so
Michelle talk tell us a little bit just
like real quick what you do and how how
you help people and um and just what
what lights what lights you on fire okay
so I am classically trained as a glass
artist so I am an artist I'd say I am
more Craftsman than fine art I produce
functional glasswar for your home but
it's very decorative and beautiful as
well uh very much a joy to have and we
teach classes we also started an online
show so I service a community by
bringing them entertainment through the
Arts and it's super fun and engaging um
because of the platforms that we work on
people can type in questions so we're
like hey you can put yourself on TV but
talk to the TV and ask us questions
because our medium is so unique and
individual that there's so many things
they want to know about they just don't
know what to ask until they watch a
couple times very cool that's awesome
and um what's your what's your uh I
guess website too where people might be
able to like find you or or glass as in
window glass glass
academy.com glass academy.com all right
awesome glass academy.com let me let me
pull this up here real quick and James
kind of dovetails right into that is how
how have you worked with Michelle and
then what do you do I know from from my
perspective you're like the the go-to
guru or the gurus when it comes to
funnels with your Lynch pin funnel uh
company and I I've seen all the like the
stuff that you've been doing with
Russell Brunson and Dan Kennedy and it's
like oh my God that's amazing tell us a
little bit about like what's going on in
your world right now as well as how
you've worked with Michelle and how you
love helping people yeah thanks for
having me brother it's been it's been
great to to see you online as well and
interact and to actually to meet you in
person um yeah for sure my my sort of uh
Epiphany story in in in the 60-second
stretch is um I was a
a software developer for over 20 years
uh my wife was a coach with Tony Robbins
for about four years she wanted to go on
her own I said I've got you I'll make
you a website I made a WordPress site it
sucked it didn't sell anything knew
nothing about marketing and sales and
had to get good fast so uh went through
a couple different um venues just ended
up with in Russell brunson's world and
really um appreciated the clarity with
which he spoke yeah um got into his
world
by being in his his uh training program
and Mastermind and and just from that
point was all in so every event that I
could go to every thing I could buy just
100% in full investment which got me to
funel hacking live 2022 and Michelle was
at phunnel hacking live 20122 and
afterwards she was in the Facebook group
for that event saying like I'm all in
I'm gonna do this who's gonna help me
and I'm like I will nice I had had like
no other customers except for my wife
oh that's that's awesome okay I love
that part I didn't know and I think that
that is so cool that like that we're
here together so yeah absolutely um I
I've delivered a lot of value and a lot
of results on the web as a web developer
so I'm I'm fully confident in in all the
technical aspects of of anything that I
do um and the marketing stuff I had been
doing for about a year with my wife
together and was like definitely
leveling up in that area but I'm like I
can I had an epiphany at FH like oh I
can do this for other people and then
you know God Universe whomever put
Michelle in front of me and I said I
will help you and we've done funnels
ever since then and um experimented
along the way and had a lot of fun yeah
yeah that's awesome um so let me I just
want to kind of pull up here one of the
like the the most recent funnel that you
that you and Michelle worked on where do
I find that online because I don't think
that's at glass academy.com where's
where's that one at do you have a link
to it Michelle or where yeah we could do
our membership one if you gave me a
second I'll yeah just a landing page or
something just to kind of see what that
looks
like yeah so this is so Russell talks
about continuity so let's
see all right give that a go cool
awesome let me yeah let me pull this up
and
then I'll kind James and I did some
funnels together and they were for
product so we we have some big shows
throughout the year so we did some
product funnels and he's like you know I
really kind of want to go to the
coaching space and then he talked about
continuity I mean James pulled all these
in he did it this is so cool yeah I love
this there was a TV show I was watching
with my wife that like on this topic and
I was just like drawn into it as well
I've always thought it's such an
interesting uh Niche and Market this is
awesome so Michelle you and I we we've
been working together for the last I
think year year and a half as far as um
in my coaching group in the client
growth accelerator program and then you
you knew you you knew me through my mom
before then right yeah I was in your
mom's business program okay cool awesome
and so like what were some of the main
things I think that you learned
through this whole process in the last
two years like if you could summarize
the last two years of like okay Michelle
prior to 2022
right and then and and then Michelle
after 2022 what were some of those
like you know like like one or two
things that really stand out to you yeah
I would say so I did some coaching in
2020 for two years and she was someone
under R Russell Brunson but what I
didn't like was she had a cookie cutter
approach and I wasn't feeling it I
wasn't ready and so your course to me is
amazing because it gives me like the
Tech link that I need or try this or you
offer suggestions like how to work AI
how to do these different things I have
it all in my head now it's James is like
pulling it out of me yeah but I have the
confidence in your program to have the
security net I need like I've talked to
you hey R stream shut down and we went
to switcher how do I do this you know I
don't pause or hesitate to have coaches
or mentors in what I want to learn so
I'm growing a YouTube our YouTube
channel is where I really want to grow
because I think we offer our best with
entertainment I mean if I can break up
your day and have you watch something
fun and Goofy that's not political or or
any heavy subject matter and get you to
chill out it's amazing yeah and so now
we have a worldwide following versus
just our business so I went from making
widgets to kind of entertaining which I
absolutely awesome love which is really
cool because my business I am PIV in
adding more entertainers and things like
that and I'm like I can see the Horizon
over even the next five years of that
coming into how to monetize
entertainment in my business and Beyond
just coaches just beyond just
education but rather like and the way I
love education is education that is
captivating that is exciting that is fun
that that we love to engage with and and
that's what I try to do here uh with
this podcast James let me ask you this
uh since
[Music]
you because you mentioned 2022 sounds
like a real Milestone moment for all
three of us for me I launched my
coaching program the accelerator program
that I have in 2022 and it was a big
transition moment for me uh where I had
taken a client from basically zero up to
over $10 million a year and I was
working almost full-time with him my
wife was running his company his name is
Rick Peno and then I was like okay I
need to Pivot into creating my own
coaching program I've been in the
industry for over 19 years okay I need
to finally like monetize all this stuff
that's up here and do something that's
how I met Michelle you had this thing
funnel hacking live um you had been
doing the web development you had your
wife as the as a coach which is also
interesting I always did all the web for
uh a lot of my clients up until 2019
when I actually said you know what I'm
not doing web
anymore I said I'm not going to like
literally be the web guy anymore I'm GNA
stop doing that because that's not my I
can do it but it's not my strong suit my
strong suit is actually communication
ideas and storytelling and so because of
because of that um I want to hear from
you James kind of what that Journey
where it's taken you in the last uh two
years here we're coming up on it was
probably what two years since then for
you yeah about about a year and a half
um but yeah I love that time pocket too
18 months for me A lot can happen and
yet it's so quick and so recent it goes
by quickly for sure um there have been a
lot of unlocks for me um personally one
is just the value of investment in self
yes I spend $30,000 a year to be in the
coaching program that I'm in yeah let me
tell you the pre previous version of me
would crap his pants if he knew that
that was going to be a reality right um
I was super just scared uh like scarcity
oriented with with money um it's been
this huge level up to be able to to well
I mean I I had a very concrete tangible
moment where I was in Russell's world I
had the books yeah which I bought
individually I didn't buy the box set
because it was too cheap to spend money
on the box Secrets I tell everybody like
they need read that if they're in my
world you know I think it's one of my
favorites it's a must for sure and the
others you got to at least know about
them and their yeah exactly but um so
there was like this this online event
where they called it the two Club Live
or something and it was basically like
some new stuff with some older fhl
videos it was this virtual event that
was there to sell the two Club coaching
program right and I didn't know that
because I was still new to this though
I'm like I'm training this three days
okay it's 200 bucks right yeah but now
you're like oh it's so obvious it makes
sense now now it's a different game um
but but I was I was there at the at the
the the crossroads where it's like okay
I see that those people know what
they're doing I can figure this out by
myself I am a I'm I'm a smart dude just
like straight up I am I can figure out a
lot of stuff right how long will it take
me how much suffering how much more will
my savings account have to be drained in
order for me to figure it the freck out
and actually make something happen right
so instead of just like going the the
Slow Burn I went went all in did the
fast burn and that going all in figuring
it out finding out what I'm freaking
made of um breaking down and like
attempting to go back to safety like
I've really had thoughts like going back
to my previous jobs and being like uh
can can I do some Contracting work with
you but then didn't you like oh yeah all
of that dude like everything for you
yeah it's been a total like spiritual
journey ever since then and now I'm at
the place where you know I'm increasing
the value that I provide and looking to
serve um higher higher value clients at
a higher level with bigger Scopes so I
have a new like uh growth opportunity in
front of me which but like I'm cool with
it I'm not fre so cool and you're not I
can tell you're not pulled in by
like the money and like it's like oh
there's all this money that I need to
make and that's one of the things I love
to surround myself with is people that
are here's the thing I'm very Money
Motivated when it comes to like okay is
this a is there going to be a return on
my investment is it worth my time right
but like you couldn't pay me enough to
do things I don't want to do and I think
that like having that that opinion um
and I've like I've sat there and done
like a thought experiment like okay how
much money would you need to pay me to
do something that I refuse to do and it
starts going into the multiple billions
and I'm just like yeah nobody's going to
pay me that anyway so
so it's like it's like knowing that
you're at that place of abundance and
then taking action on the things that
maybe you've been fearful of or the um
the familiar behaviors that were used to
doing there's a lady I I literally just
started her book recently um she was the
head of culture at Tik Tok and she was a
consultant for Facebook um her name is
uh M Mel not Michelle Mel Ashman and I
started reading her book what would you
do if you weren't afraid now I've only
gotten about halfway through it but what
I loved about it was the first intro
spoke to my soul so much because she was
like I spent years in therapy and this
is all the lessons that they couldn't
help me with because I solved a lot of
the stuff but the pro and and eventally
four chapters in she's like you just
have to do it scared you do you just
have to do the stuff that you're
terrified of even when you're scared to
do it and you got to like learn how to
get tools to regulate the emotions so
that you're not stopped by the fear as
far as it goes and and and I'll and I'll
just tell you A lot of people who listen
to this podcast they know my story my
background things like that I've just
had crippling fear at every level in my
business the reason why I tell people
this the reason why I've been in the
industry 21
years lot of
success um
but not for myself as much until the
last two years because I was always
helping other people because I was too
afraid and didn't think I was worthy of
my own success I always I like I helped
multiple people make 1020 million
dollars a year and and and and yet I
never really took those strategies and
applied them for myself the most money I
ever made was a quarter million dollars
a year now I could consistently make a
quarter a million dollars a year in my
sleep but it was like I was terrified to
do the stuff
to go beyond that as far as that goes
and so what are some of the lessons that
Michelle I want to ask you this that you
have found when it comes to doing the
stuff when you're afraid to do it or
maybe it's not even fear sometimes fear
manifests in very different words Fear
Can manifest as wisdom sometimes the
word I find some people they're like
well it's wise to not do this and I'm
like M nope you're actually afraid is
what it is you're not actually wise
you're using wisdom as a crutch for your
fear because it looks really good and
Noble to say oh it's wisdom for me to go
back to the old clients right because in
some people's minds financially that
would be wise but we're choosing to live
a different life we're choosing to live
a life that is different than what most
people are willing to live and so in in
our world it's not wise to go backwards
to where we've come from right and so
Michelle what are some of those lessons
that maybe you've learned about taking
action uh and as well as the
accountability with
that so taking action Jame I'm gonna I
wrote down your comment go back to
safety and it's like oh my God you did
it like your thoughts were so quick I
was like eight years into our business
and I'm like I can't do this anymore
like this is too stressful yeah um I'm
an artist you know so first off you come
out of the gate with starving artist on
your head I worked at a Historical
Museum the Henry Ford which is like this
famous Museum in Michigan oh my gosh my
childhood memories there I
know Jeremiah's from
Michigan one of my favorite places in
the world was there I mean Henry Ford
whatever people say about him he was
beyond his years I mean it's fascinating
he would take buildings and transport
them yeah and when I work there you
could go up in the library and look at
any book so I mean I wanted to be a
major what do you do with that and so I
moved out of the house at 17 went to
college worked a full-time job was
humping it and then was just like at
what point do you settle in so I look at
my gifts and talents I loved history so
I got a job there there was an opening
in the glass shop wow so this is that
were you there in the 90s yeah you
probably my family was there at watching
the glass shop in the 90s at Henry Ford
my mom and I I left dad all that so we
we probably cross path a few times
that's so funny I mean it's an amazing
place and if you look where you're
inspired you know what were the chances
there was an opening I started it there
were six of us I was the one who really
understood the medium maybe I'm good at
this you know full-time job eventually
um all the things you want in security
how many glass blowers do you guys know
like to get a full-time job in a museum
as a glass blower with full benefits
yeah you do that and then what did I do
I went employed right so my husband was
an entrepreneur I was having babies I
homeschooled the kids I would work at
night when they went to sleep like we
built this business and throughout it I
intuitively had to say over and over
where is my strength and trust my
process and trust me and that will EB
and flow and dip throughout your life
and you know we landed now at this place
where I met James at funnel hacking and
I realized this is bigger than what I
can do
and I need to bring people in I mean
that's so out of my comfort zone I love
talking to people but at heart I'm an
introvert I need to sit down and do the
work I write the copy I I can drive the
ship but I don't want to manage a huge
team so it's like how do you find this
balance of your intrinsic talents and
then work with people to bring them out
that's awesome let me ask you this
Michelle in the last two years what are
some of the things like again prior to
2022 to and then like today lessons of
things that you're like okay I didn't
realize I had this fear worry or block I
guess we could call it blocks even right
things that were blocking you from where
you're at today that could be even like
one lesson that you could pass on to
people that are listening to this
podcast because I think that's really G
to be some of the value that we can
provide to to them I got the best one
because I just learned this yesterday it
was talking about beliefs and it was
saying like when you have a belief this
pen will write my full notebook like it
can write that it's got that much ink
like you look at your beliefs is that
true yeah it could probably write a
whole notebook could it write 10
notebooks probably not so you look at
your beliefs as they come up and you see
if they're real now Russell just is
doing the thing where he's posting every
day and he's putting these challenges he
has a book club he has all these things
and I'm blending all those conversations
together being around like-minded people
I like totally resonate with what he's
saying
and one of them was a money challenge
and you had to write down your husband's
beliefs your spouse's beliefs you are
money beliefs as a child and when she
wrote that down it took it to another
level and I recognized I'm like oh my
God like I took that belief on because I
wasn't an entrepreneur but my husband
was so the belief is anyone you do
business with is like a crook or like
they're gonna steal money from you or
like you gota he had very hard beliefs
that were not my own and so the really
cool thing from 2020 is my guiding the
company I choose and James is a great
example I choose to work from a place of
love like I want to give value and serve
James how can I help you like I comment
on his Facebook page I make sure I'm
active in his community I try to boost
him up so that people know he exists
yeah um and I think those are the things
those are the beliefs and the challenges
that we can look at them just because I
believed in yesterday today's a new day
and I can change that belief with my own
thought process that's awesome uh what
about you James as far as just like
blocks that maybe in the last two years
three years that have
like been moved for you like mountains
and stuff and I feel like we always we
don't know there's a mountain there and
then it's like oh this is it and then
you move it and it's like there's the
gold mine because you moved it and
there's a gold mine underneath the
mountain that you didn't know was there
what what were those for you
well through this process of needing to
add more value to the world I have had a
continual process of
removing actions and behaviors and
thoughts that inhibit progress yes very
good uh I used
to play a lot of video games don't
anymore yeah I used to watch a lot of
movies I don't anymore yeah I used to
drink um a beer to on most nights yeah I
don't anymore I used to do so I so and
that's like the preal so all of those
things were minor escapes from my
own lack of belief my own negative
assessment of status and and deserv
ability and I had one that was still
remaining which was uh
work I would often
have a trigger or an experience that
would just be like okay I need to just
if I go work right now I will be
perceived by my family and others around
me as
valuable which gave me a stability and
certainty yeah yeah so the major one
that I am I've had the like Revelation
and am slowly
fixing by bringing on contractors and
bringing on um other ways to delegate
and Outsource and and remove myself from
the the kind of like day-to-day doing
yeah so that I can serve and grow the
company but also so that I don't have
that as another hiding place oh yeah
that's good I love that I love that I
think that's really good like where are
the places that we go to hide and
Escape um
and I I teach this often for people that
to really come out in your fullest self
I I there's a book that I love about the
value of play and that can look
different for everybody and what it is
is it's like it's
unstructured time where you just sort of
let your childlike Essence come
through and you're not focused on okay I
got to grind and work and do this and do
all this so like what's what's so
interesting is is that looks different
for everybody I'm finding it looks way
different for me like than 99% of the
business owners that I'm that I meet uh
but it uniquely works for me which is
really cool um and one of the number one
lessons that I always point to as it's
funny I was telling my mom one day I
need to write a book called Rich mom
Poor
Dad because I had a brinded dad who
worked in Corporate America he adopted
me and honestly was not a role model A
man that I can look up to somebody that
and he him and my mom divorced nine
years ago uh I saw him two years ago it
was I shook his hand and that was like
the only interaction we had was that
because his he he operates in this um
just victim mentality constantly as far
as that goes and and I know why that is
I I've really made peace with where that
comes from because it's the only thing
that he knows how to do and then my mom
built these businesses that were
millions and millions and millions of
dollars and she had all these lessons
that she imparted into me one of them
was always this is that she could grind
it out like anybody else like nobody's
business uh and I remember seeing her
working 90 to 100 hours a week when I
was a uh 12 13 years old what was
interesting was I respected that a lot
in her my young Brothers weren't too
they were they were more needy needing
her more as a mom but I respected that
hustle in her at that age and I was like
oh wow wait that's what it takes to
provide for a family working 90 to 100
hours a week and that was ingrained in
me until a couple years ago and now like
today I only work maybe 10 to 15 hours a
week in my business and I'm working to
even pull back more to where we're only
working
um f I'm only working 5 to 10 hours a
week in my business as far as that goes
and then the rest of the time what am I
doing with that whatever the heck I want
to do that could that could look
like hanging out with my wife and son
that also could look like watching a
movie playing video games if that's what
I want to do in that moment to spur on
creativity um and and that's one of the
things I teach people too is you can use
entertainment as a tool to activate
creative parts of your brain and then
kind of flow into that so it's not an
escape but it's like a flip where it's
like it's more of a creative Outlet
um from there though my mom always
taught me was this lesson shrink
everything
down to the lowest common denominator of
where you're not working or grinding and
you can get the same amount done with as
few working hours as
possible and and I joke of of it as like
some people would see that as laziness
because the way that she would do it is
literally she would do this and what
would she do it the rest of the time she
would watch Netflix the the time my mom
would do this she would just sit there
and watch Netflix and and it actually
got to the point where her body forced
her on bed rest she almost died she had
14 autoimmune diseases she was on bed
rest and she literally worked herself
out of this Chrysalis of dying my mother
did and rebirthing herself into a brand
new person Michelle has seen that whole
process as far as that goes and becoming
like the grandmother she was born to be
becoming the mother that like I always
knew she could be as a kid like I always
saw her potential as a mom as a kid and
had these Rosy colored glasses but like
in the last two three years she's really
stepped into that and the lessons for me
were always I I always saw that happen
when she would pull back and work
less when she would not chase the money
where she would not chase the um what is
it it's really it's it's the addictive
dopamine hit that happens from
Achievement from doing something from
accomplishing something from feeling
like I'm enough and finding our
worthiness in what we do as far as that
goes and and and I'll tell you um I'm in
the process right now of finding that
for myself you know I feel like James
like I I'd love to even just like learn
more of that from you as far as that
goes and Michelle just how how you've
been able to have confidence to take
action in things that you didn't know
what the outcome was for me it's I'm I'm
the biggest hypocrite in this one by the
way because I preach a message of taking
action all the time and I'm finally like
admitting to the fact of my own
hypocracy in this uh because quite
frankly I I I think it's important to do
so I preach a message of going after
your dreams not worrying about what the
outcome is and yet most of my actions I
take every day are calculated I have
certainty in I know what the outcome is
and very rarely do I take an action that
I don't think I know what it's going to
be until recently where I'm like you
know what like God I need you to show me
what the next step is because I don't
know what it is I don't know what the
next thing to do is love this that's why
we're talking right now look let me see
okay I do a coach and right before a
call it's a horrible drawing I'm an nerv
it's a horrible drawing but here's me
the human not knowing oh my God James
speak at hfl all right here's me the
human I want to do these things I want
to speak at hfl my higher source whether
that's God or whatever it is cannot can
direct me I'm a human I don't know I am
on this Earth experiencing living life
but if I trust and
allow here's to my coach allow no joke
like if I allow the process to happen
and unfold and I don't push it I just
trust where do I get that knowing from
you guys play video games which you'll
never catch me on one but uh I like to
be in the in the dirt so my I volunteer
in a flower farm I just changed up my
whole front yard so I can get my hands
in the dirt and then now I'm documenting
that process so I can show others like I
don't know how to do this I have no idea
but I'm just gonna start and like James
you post every day all right that's what
I learned last year at funnel hacking
post every day so now I'm like out there
with my Instagram Jeremiah I asked you
what selfie stick to buy I'm like how do
I do this yeah and I mean honestly you
guys like if I can do it I'm not like 20
I didn't grow up with this crap like
this is so out of my wheelhouse but I'm
like okay I have value and it's not
doing any good in my brain I need to
share this value how do I get this out
there and I'm relying on you guys and
being vulnerable here being like help
like if I need help and you just got to
start I mean you just got to figure it
out and and walk the path this brings me
joy I'm going here I want to eat a
cookie this brings me joy that is like
where it helps I love that for for for
me I found that like gardening is a
great way to it's a great Outlet as far
as that goes um for you and for I know
my mom loves gardening and stuff like
that it's funny I've been studying a lot
of the top video games right now on the
mobile app store are farming and
gardening games so it's almost like this
idea of like people want to grow
something whether it's virtual or it's
in the real world we have this like
Consciousness in the world where we want
to grow something whether it be families
communities uh our are and oftentimes
it's not growing our self but how can we
impact those around us you know when if
you look at like Millennials I don't
know what the right term is but some of
them aren't having children but they
have a shitload of plants and why do
they right and dogs and cats and all
exactly the same uh spirit I would say
energy it's the same energy exactly I
mean a new Leaf is unfurling and you're
just like oh my God look at this beauty
like you had nothing to do with it you
just allowed it to happen and you got to
experience it and I think when we see
that it helps us understand I'm
blossoming too today I'm a new Leaf I
can go forward with this it's okay
that's awesome James I got a a question
for you this one might be out of left
field but I I I think you you can answer
it beautifully for everybody what are
some of your ways that you have found um
and and I'm asking you this because a
lot of people that I have met who are
from like their web development they're
traditionally like a software developer
World they don't know how to tap into
that intuition and hearing that inner
voice and it's almost like I've tried to
explain it and they're like nope it's
not for me it doesn't even exist in my
world and I'm like I get that but like I
know people that have been able to do
that what are some strategies for you to
be able to hear that inner voice for you
okay well the the truth is that I was
that guy I didn't think I had an inner
voice um so the the the real answer is
um I don't know if you guys are familiar
with the term complex postraumatic
stress disorder
CP yeah yeah cool uh I knew I liked
you uh so like a lot of a lot like um
um suppression of of of voice and a lot
of like whatever the thing is is wrong
so I kind of like sought others and
would um seek to get approval from
others a lot of like external validation
a lot of that stuff that was my world
for a long time um super vulnerably like
I had a moment with my wife where we
were not good at all and like we were
kind of on the edge and I just got to
the point where like I cannot [__] do
this anymore and and prior to this I if
you would ask me I'd say I was an
atheist no spiritual
connection and I just said like God I
give up like I can't do this
anymore I I you like I have to I have to
whatever you say and that's when
everything switched for me W that's when
I started just going with it that's when
I started just like exposing my like
instead of this I was doing this and
where wher wherever it takes me wherever
it leads me and I'm doing that now so I
had don't have any strategies I don't
have any tips and tricks I don't have
any anything other than you know for me
what worked was just keep going being as
as and I I value how driven I was I I
value like the the consistency and the
persistence and the ability to to take
something like I was dragging so much
freaking weight throughout the entire
span right that that's laudable right
and dropping all that so I can go faster
and go higher it's just a brilliant
brilliant thing the surrender yeah
aspect is a big part of it hey you guys
got to do some AI generated I wanted to
do a picture of baggage and dropping
that right we need that like on our
Facebook pages dropping that baggage and
just allowing it to come through yeah
letting go and that's something that I
that I really I I teach often but I find
people don't don't resonate with it's
funny my spiritual background I grew up
in this super crazy hyper controlling
cultic Christian Church that quite
frankly I should not believe in God
because they were insane
and like just like abusive nuts people
that like are deeply concerning that I
like grew up around I'd say that I was
raised by wolves because these were just
like devouring people exploiting people
for money using religion all of that and
now here I am like teaching coaching and
all of this from this crazy background
that I grew up in and yet I still
believe in God but it's not like the way
that I grew up in I had to unlearn
everything that I knew about God which
was like not even true it was this like
it was this fabrication that they
invented in church to be able to control
people and I was just like okay like
that's not actually how God really is
and then learning how to come in touch
with my inner
self and then that connection to the
Divine the connection and the way I say
it is like the
universe God all all of that together
are
interconnected so much so that it's like
I find sometimes when we separate the
two oh it's the universe or God I'm like
it's both you
know and so for
me it's just like what am I feeling in
this moment when I'm the most calm when
I'm the most peaceful when I'm not
vibrating and feeling anxious and that t
that takes a while to get there I think
for a lot of people it's not an
overnight thing for me it was learning
to love
myself the way that the people that I
looked up to loved
me and it was like the people that made
me feel the most safe there was a there
was a man that I I had worked for him
and his wife uh for years uh Danny and
Hans Johnson but he had a a masculine
presence that I just respected so much
and it was like how would I hug myself
if I was the energy that I always felt
from him of protection and safety and
wrapping myself in my own protection and
safety as far as that goes and that like
unlocked something in me where I felt
like my personality had been held
dormant and captive in a prison for like
15 years and a lot of people don't know
this about my story um I don't talk
about it that lightly but I was I was
facing seriously uh life in prison for
for a while um I I had made a mistake on
social media I had said something that
you should never post on social media uh
that I didn't know violated the Patriot
Act I didn't know that you can't post
even joking a threat against a president
I didn't know that I thought it was like
free speech and they're like nope it's
not we're going to arrest you and by the
way you're facing life in prison for
this and I was like crap I was like I
was drunk one night and like and that
was my whole that was my whole legal
defense I was drunk wasted out of my
mind and they were like okay they
investigated and they found out they're
like Jeremiah is like a very good
upstanding person and but I was like
okay I'm actually thankful that we have
a system that investigated this and took
this seriously too as far as that goes
but I was terrified and then that fear
all of that that was 15 years ago locked
me up into this this T like I was so
afraid to make any mistakes with what I
say and then the skill set that came out
of that was sales copyrighting and being
able to communicate on podcasts and to
be able to communicate with with content
and to teach people but I was so afraid
to say the wrong thing at the wrong
moment in time I mean there are there
are people who
I've lost business with when they found
out my past 15 years ago and the mistake
that I made and they're just like I
literally can't associate with you like
I I literally they're like I need you to
delete that recording that we just did
because my name can't be next to you
because of the connections that I found
out they were like doing stuff with the
government and all that now one of my
closest friends he it does stuff with
presidents and politicians all the time
and he's like not concerned about it so
I'm like it just some people are part of
your tribe and others are not and not
everybody's supposed to go with you long
term into things and I think that's one
of the things is learning to let go
that's where I'm trying to like Land
This Plane is learning to let go of what
what we thought how things should be in
our
lives right we have this vision of like
oh it should be this
way it should be this way for you
know for me I should be wealthier than I
am
today and I could sit there and beat
myself up for hours and hours and hours
and upset that I don't have more zeros
in my bank account today yeah but I'm
going to interrupt you because you are
extremely
wealthy child you know what I mean we
need to stop looking at wealth dollars
in the bank I know great health a
Vibrant Community you are extremely
wealthy exactly and the time Freedom
that I have too literally I don't do
anything that I don't want to do at any
moment in time I can say that like I
just choose what I do every moment in
time my mom was adding it up she was
like if she knew what she knew today
when she started in business her net
worth would be between 250 $500 million
but it's not because she gave it all
away to these churches she gave it all
away to all these these people and she
never invested a dime of it until like
two years ago my mom never invested that
was if she didn't do that she wouldn't
be where she is now have to trust that
the past and so where I'm saying is is
that I'm I'm I'm I'm landing this to we
got to let go of the should do yeah and
the past stories of gosh I made this
mistake 15 years ago I made made this
mistake 10 years ago I made this mistake
two years ago I want to I want I want to
say this I'm I'm almost getting like a
word for some people right now you might
have joined a coaching program two years
ago with a coach that led you down a
path that lost you a ton of
money and now you're hearing this right
now and you're like okay if I had found
James two years ago I would be a
millionaire today if I had met Michelle
I would be a completely different person
than I am today two years ago but
instead I followed this path and we end
up feeling this guilt and this shame and
this worry and we're just like I just
wish things were different can I tell
you this just for those that are
listening what
if everything LED you up to this moment
in time right now for the purpose to
launch you to where you were supposed to
go
yeah and learning to let go of that
baggage you know when we when when we
look at a rocket
ship I I I I love Elon Musk and SpaceX
but if you look at the stages of a
rocket ship they have to let go of the
booster
Rockets that's what that's there's all
these rockets that are and what ends up
landing on the moon is this little tiny
thing at the very top of the
rocket and and like 90% of all of the
stuff that they build to even get it out
there just disappears and falls back and
nobody is concerned about it but they
spent all of this time building up to
that moment in time and and it's funny
it's such a picture we use the word
launch when it comes to marketing when
it comes to entertainment you know we're
gonna do a movie launch a movie premiere
we're going to launch a video game we're
going to launch our stream we're going
to launch our funnel we're going to
launch our course we're going to launch
our coaching program all these different
things and what's interesting is all of
the stuff that you kind of do in the
process if you look back at the last 10
20 years of your
life it when it starts to fall away and
you got that little piece right there
that's where you end up landing
on the moon or Mars and you build a base
there and that's what then takes you to
the next level which might take you to
another dimension like alpha centari or
another okay that's where I get all
nerdy out and stuff like that as I start
like thinking in these directions of
becoming a multiplanetary species and
all of this I literally find
parallels in the desire of humanity to
land on other
planets to what we have to do as humans
in our transformation process it's so
interesting as far as this goes letting
go of the heavy baggage that propelled
us to where we were meant to be what if
that baggage was the propellent that you
needed I like to add something because I
feel like you can have access to that
sort of realization without having to
have like a major catastrophe or
something one of the lessons that we
learned from Tony Robbins is to um in
any moment in any catastrophe like it
could be literally like you know um a
close family member dying yeah how how
is this the best thing that could have
happened to
me how is that wait say that again how
is this the best thing that could have
happened how is this the best thing that
100% yeah you can you can take any
moment um and and find the good in it
find it's it's like you know we there's
so much power and so much leverage in
questions because it does take us out of
our uh negative kind of default mode and
kind of switches it and has us look for
the the positive the bright so it's like
how how is the best thing possible to
have happened to me
yes you that is always accessible to you
every moment of every single day like
meditate on that
question for like like for me like I
just want to go lay in my swimming pool
now and just think about like how has
everything that's happened to me up
until this moment in time been the best
moment possible for me how has listening
to this podcast for you as a listener
been the best moment possible for the
last 46
minutes and think about that and
then can we accelerate that what's a way
to accelerate
that learning from other people's
mistakes coaching
mentoring yeah working with people that
have walked a journey that have been to
Hellen
back that have actually then been to
heaven and back I think is what we can
say as well because for me it's like
I've been to Hell and back and then I've
been to heaven and back and I've kind of
figured out okay what's in both
dimensions and then we bring that
together into the beautiful um
experiences that we get to provide for
people whatever our story is that we
tell
people and I think that storytelling
really is the vehicle that
shapes people's lives that helps
thinking it's a way that we can pass on
to people our experiences without them
having to experience it because you can
listen to a story that somebody tells in
five to 10 minutes and they can take you
on a
journey and then you feel like you felt
what they experienced but you also
learned the same lessons that they
experienced and that's something that I
share with everybody when it comes to
writing sales copy when it comes to
doing a webinar when it comes to
pitching a product is you have to mirror
the story of your prospect back to them
in a way that they feel like you
understand so deeply what they've
experienced that trust is built like
that that's how you can build trust in
five to 10 minutes with people in a vssl
how do you build trust in 60 seconds on
a Facebook ad by learning how to tell
better stories and then learning how to
articulate and communicate that way now
that now that's a process that that's
what I love to Mentor people on that's
what we work with you through in my
coaching program that's that's that I
would say that's the number one thing
that lights me on fire is storytelling
more than anything else that's why I
love video games that's why I even have
a a book right here I'm I'm reading it's
a Netflix special right now I recommend
everybody check out the three body
problem it's such a powerful story uh
I'm reading it right
now it's it's it's actually a it's a
parable of we got to look at for AI and
technology and where everything's headed
as far as that goes
so James thank you for being here I just
appreciate you and I just want to honor
you and just say thank you for your
presence on this podcast episode
grateful to be here thank you for the
invitation I feel is is there any kind
of final words that you want to share
with anybody that's on here just to kind
of wrap this
up what's wrong is always a available
but what's right is always available as
well oo that's good you get to choose
mhm and again the previous version of me
would have fought you at that notion
that I I can't I there is no choice here
this is just happening
yeah yeah it's true it's but there
there's always a choice and the um
ability to create a gap between the the
sort of stimulus and the response want
and to choose um it's that is the
definition of mental health to me that's
so good I love that I'm GNA I'm gonna
like meditate on that after this call
like what you just said that's awesome
Michelle what about you any final any
final thoughts yeah I liked uh what you
said what if because that's a big thing
I play with what if and I'm gonna add to
James's what if this was happening for
me right what if roadblocks came up
because it's not the way you need to go
what if this was an opportunity to Pivot
what if this
was showing me A New Path what if I
allow it to open so I like what
if that's awesome James where what's
your contact info website I just want to
put it on the screen here uh just go to
lynchpin funnel. comom it's kind of C me
Lyn pinf funnel. comom yep um you find
me on Facebook James
Curran yes let me let's see
lynchpin funnel. comom people might not
know how to spell lynchpin Lynch
pins.com
[Music]
let me see if this pulls up here I like
to like there we go I do stuff that I
don't know how it works half the time
and I just try to test it out so I love
that's like it's one of my like favorite
things to do is just try to Break Stuff
really quick so there you go Lyin
funnel. it's on the recording that's
where everybody can can can check check
that out if I go
here uh to lynchpin funnel. there's your
face right there I'm going to pull it up
on the screen
here
um home
of I like the coffe cut James it's like
sit and have a coffee with me yeah right
it yeah there we go so there's your
there's your site right there there's
you I love that photo and so join the
Lynch pin funnel hackers Collective is
this where you want them to jump in yeah
that's a free group um there's a a free
lunch pin funel right there um depending
on what time you know when this when
this airs we we're we're doing
challenges a lot of challenge right now
there's one that's gonna happen next
week but if we miss that one then we can
probably month but yeah and I've been
watching like the ones that you that you
create and all of that they're perfectly
aligned with the like what I what I
teach people in here and and what I do I
mean most of what I teach you'll find it
like a lot of the Dan Kennedy stuff a
lot of the Russell Brunson um Alex
Hermos all that kind of kind of stuff
but I love the mithy funnel too having a
a free gift that you give along with
that can you explain a little bit on
like how that works just briefly and
then how people like what you can do
with people to kind of make that come
together absolutely so Miffy stands for
most accredible free gift ever it's
essentially a bribe um then kened will
often call it a widget it's just some
sort of package of stuff that is really
cool um one term we also use in the
industry is it's useful but incomplete
so it's some kind of bribe some kind of
cool thing something that's highly
desirable that you can only get if you
join a membership or or start a
continuity thing so yeah people I love
to include my best course yeah but that
I know that they're going to need more
support with yeah yeah that um one thing
that so we we did a miy from for
Michelle and one of the things that's
really cool about that is you know she's
a glass artist that creates original
glass pieces so you literally like she
puts this stuff in this offer it's not
going in her shop it's not going in her
store you can only get thing so that's
really enticing and and um another way
to think about it is it's something that
takes you from uh at a scale from seven
to 10 if you're at a seven the Miffy
takes you to a 10 okay cool awesome
that's amazing yeah that's that's that's
kind of how I I picked it up as well
when I I watched some of different
trainings on that and so I I love that
um we did that for years like lot of
stuff with my mom and then I realized I
had like completely moved away from
doing that in my business and I was like
duh why am I not doing this you know so
that's amazing if you want somebody that
can help you build this together so you
don't have to do the work Tech stuff's
not your thing go check out lynchpin
funnel. comom with James here he's your
guy he will take care of you I know that
for a fact so all right everybody thank
you for being here thank you both of
y'all and grow your life
we'll talk soon by the way if this
episode has helped you at all share it
with somebody don't keep it to yourself
and we'll see you on the next episode
we'll talk soon bye
[Music]